《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情提要
HELO: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
舰队里的一些人相信 地球的传说
Some people in the Fleet believe that the legend of Earth held,
也许是我们生存下去的最好保证
perhaps, the greatest promise for our survival.
知道怎么找到它吗?
Do you know how to find it?
不太清楚
Not really, no.
有个希望 如果你知道去地球的方法
There was a hope, my hope, that if you knew the way to Earth,
那能确保让你活得更久一些
it would justify keeping you alive a little longer.
我不知道地球的具体位置
Now when I say that I do not know exactly where Earth is,
并不意味我不知道
that is not to say that I do not know
大量关于地球大概位置的信息
a very great deal about its probable location.
那艘基地之星
DORAL: A Baseship,
就是我们派过去调查狮子星云中脉冲星的那艘
the one we sent to investigate the pulsars in the Lion nebula,
我们失去了联络
we've lost contact.
失踪的基地之星
CAPRICA SIX: The missing Baseship,
可能感染了某种病毒
it's been infected by some kind of disease.
如果一个感染的赛昂人死亡
If an infected Cylon dies
把病毒带着一起返回了复活船
and carries this disease with them into a Resurrection ship,
那可能会快速蔓延 会威胁到我们整个族群
it could rapidly spread, potentially infecting our entire race.
只要我们其中一个复活了 那个病毒就会跟随而入
If one of us is resurrected, the disease will follow.
没有一个赛昂人能不被感染地登上那艘船
Then no Cylon can board that ship without risking infection.
我去 是的 我去
I'll go. Yes, I'll go.
我可以去那个基地之星
I can go to the Baseship.
我可以对上面的赛昂人进行观察 检查他们的身体状况
I can make observations about the Cylons, their physical condition,
带回关于让你们都在恐惧的病毒的信息
bring back information about this disease which now threatens all of you.
你知道这是什么吗?
BALTAR: Do you know what this is?
肯定是某种信标
It must be some kind of beacon.
第13部落遗留下来的
It must have been left here by the Thirteenth Tribe.
那个信标带有病毒 是人类留下来毁灭我们的
A beacon carried the disease, left by some humans like you to destroy us.
你没发现被感染船上有什么可疑的吗?
You noticed nothing suspicious on the infected ship?
没有什么特别的
Nothing whatsoever.
我和你一样困惑
I am just as baffled as you are.
就如那份手稿所写
RACETRACK: Just like the scriptures say.
就在那里  狮头星云  还有闪耀的眼睛
There it is, the Lion's Head nebula and the Blinking Eye.
我的天 那是通往地球的道路
Holy crap, it's the road to Earth!
这里是战斗分队  A计划准备完毕
APOLLO: This is Combat, dressed and ready, plan A.
我们正在接近基地之星
We are approaching the Baseship.
这很反常
It is just so wrong.
到底里面发生了什么?
What the hell happened here?
不管发生了什么 对我们来说都是新的机遇
ATHENA: Whatever this is, it's something new.
执行
Go.
阿波罗  这是卡拉狄加  开始行动
Apollo, Galactica. You are cleared hot.
收到 卡拉狄加
APOLLO: Roger that, Galactica.
我们现在离它相当近
We're in pretty close now.
可用肉眼观察它 飞船看起来没有战斗能力了
By the look of it, that ship's in no condition to put up a fight.
我从未见过这种情况  我们继续吗?
I've never seen anything like this. Shall we proceed?
坐好了 伙计们
Hang on, guys!
多加小心  阿波罗
HELO: Use extreme caution, Apollo.
设置防御带  准备进入
APOLLO: Set perimeter. Up inside, everyone.
卡拉狄加 我是阿波罗 我们进来了
Galactica, Apollo. We're in.
卡拉狄加 我是阿波罗 没有生命迹象
Galactica, Apollo. No sign of life.
飞船看起来是被遗弃并关闭了
Ship appears to be abandoned and powering down.
见鬼了?
APOLLO: What the hell?
上帝 这里发生过什么?
Gods. What happened here?
我不知道 但他们该死的复活船有得忙了
I don't know, but their frakking Resurrection ship's gonna overheat.
卡拉狄加  我是阿波罗  我们到了控制中心
Galactica, Apollo. We've reached the control center.
有30...也许是40具人形赛昂的尸体
Thirty, maybe forty dead skin jobs.
马赛厄斯 设置防御带!
Mathias, set a perimeter!
莎伦...雅典娜  去看看能从电脑那里找到什么
Sharon, Athena, see what you can pick up in the computers.
分成3个火力小分队  每个队守一个门  快去
MATHIAS: Three fire teams, each doorway. Go!
是 长官
MARINE: Yes, sir.
好的 我准备连入数据库
ATHENA: Okay, I'm gonna try to call up the database.
如果我能联接上 把固体继电器导入那边的液体中
If I get a connection, put the SSR leads in the water over there.
降低错误检校级别 来扩大数据传输带宽
Reduce the error correction levels for highest throughput.
你确定想这么做吗?
RACETRACK: You sure you wanna do that?
就这么做了
ATHENA: It's how it works.
你还好吗?
You okay?
还好  数据库已经差不多都损坏了
Yeah. The data points are almost completely corroded.
我不知道我能够得到什么信息 但我会试的
I don't know if I'm gonna get much out of here, but let's try.
进行得怎么样了?
What is going on?
已进入所有防御带
MARINE: We're now inside all perimeters.
妈的! 这个还活着呢!
Frak me! This one's alive!
这儿! 我们找到个活的!
We got a live one over here!
丹利 彼得斯 掩护大家!
MATHIAS: Danelli, Peters, cover the Major!
他们是活的!
APOLLO: They're alive!
卡拉狄加 我是阿波罗 我们找到1 2 3 4
Galactica, Apollo. We've got one, two, three, four,
5个活的赛昂人
five living skin jobs down here.
我重复一次 5个活着的
I say again, five... Five living.
你们开火了吗?
HELO: Are you taking fire?
没有 没有
Negative, negative.
他们看起来状况不妙
They seem in pretty bad shape.
不要大意 如果他们有什么危险举动
Don't take any chances. If they make any threatening moves...
相信我吧
APOLLO: You can trust me on that one.
趴下
MARINE: Stay down!
上尉  我们该怎么办?  要把他们带出去吗?
Major, what do we do? Should we take them out?
不要开火 不要开火!
APOLLO: Hold your fire. Hold your fire!
别动 妈的
MATHIAS: Stay, you frakkers!
我说了别开火!
I said hold your fire!
赐予我们...力量...智慧...
NO. 6:Grant us the strength, the wisdom.
他们在干什么呢?
APOLLO: What are they doing?
最重要的...承诺的量度
Above all, a measure...
嗨 雅典娜 你在干什么?  雅典娜!
Hey, Athena, what are you doing? Athena!
你在干什么?  雅典娜!
What are you doing? Athena!
赐予我们...力量...智慧...
Grant us the strength, the wisdom...
叛徒
Traitor.
拯救你自己吧
Save yourself.
从何说起?
From what?
离我们远点
Keep away from us.
这儿发生什么了?
What happened here?
一个信标 我们把它带上船了
NO. 6: The beacon, we brought it onboard.
它有病毒
It carried a disease.
我们被感染了
We're infected.
感染?
Infected?
噢 他妈的!
Son-of-a-bitch!
行了 行了 行了!
Okay, okay, okay!
冷静下来!
Settle down, keep your heads!
看好门 看好门!
Watch the doorways! Get the doorways!
卡拉狄加  我是阿波罗  我们这儿有个状况
Galactica, Apollo. We have a situation down here.
那些赛昂人感染了一种病毒
The Cylons have been infected with a disease.
我们都暴露在这里了 我们都暴露在这里了
We have all been exposed. We've all been exposed.
他们登船后一定要执行隔离程序
COTTLE: They'll have to come aboard under quarantine procedures.
从机库里清理出一条路通到医务室 并要消毒
Clear a path from the hangar deck to sickbay and sterilize it,
而猛禽机跟随他们后面进来
and the Raptors after they're in.
就交给我处理
I'll handle that.
他们要隔离多长时间呢?
How long will they have to stay in quarantine?
在血检结果出来前  我也不知道要多长时间
I won't know that until I do the blood work.
可能几天或几星期  这是没法说的事情
Could be days, weeks, there's no way to tell.
你说他们是被那个信标感染的?
You said they picked up this disease from a beacon?
是赛昂人说的
According to the Cylons.
能得到病原体的话就好了
Always good to have the source of the pathogen.
你能把它给弄到卡拉狄加上吗?
Can you bring it aboard Galactica?
不 太危险了 要限制暴露的危险
No, too dangerous. I want to limit our exposure.
囚犯怎么样了?
What about the prisoners?
囚犯?
Prisoners?
他们体内的病毒要更高级一些
The disease is more advanced in their systems,
所以我有了点想法 看看接下来病情会如何发展
so it'll give me at least an idea of what to expect as it progresses.
而且等他们死后 就能知道我们的人能活多久了
And when they die, it'll tell me how long our people have to live.
有多少囚犯?
How many prisoners?
你抓到多少个?
How many you got?
阿波罗 这是卡拉狄加 第一次检查
HELO: Apollo, Galactica. Alpha check.
卡拉狄加 我们看到你们了 正在接近右舷机库
Galactica. We have you in visual range. Approaching starboard hangar.
阿波罗  那是什么?
HELO: Apollo, what was that?
基地之星释放出大量能量
GAETA: Massive energy discharge from the Baseship!
它爆炸了 长官
It exploded, sir.
阿波罗 这是卡拉狄加  你们大家都还好吧?
Apollo, Galactica. You all right out there?
嗯  没事  我们还在这儿
Yeah, affirmative. We're still here.
发生什么了?
What the hell happened?
基地之星爆炸了 一定是自毁
Baseship exploded. Must've self-destructed.
你们这些家伙真走运 能平安出来
You guys are lucky you got out when you did.
收到
Roger that.
我相信没什么问题
Nothing the matter, I trust?
我们有些问题
We have some questions.
为了背叛我们  你计划了多久   盖尤斯?
How long have you planned to betray us, Gaius?
有趣
Funny.
你当然是在开玩笑了
You're joking, of course.
你这是对你自己不负责任了
You're only making this harder on yourself.
等一等
Wait a minute.
我是非常非常合作的 自从我来了以后
I have been more than very accommodating since I arrived here.
我帮你们找到了莎伦的孩子
I helped you find Sharon's baby.
我还帮你们搞到了通往地球的地图
I've helped you with the map towards Earth.
我们知道信标的事情了 盖尤斯
We know about the beacon, Gaius.
你知道它在那儿的 你知道那里有致命的病毒
You knew it was out there. You knew it contained a deadly virus.
不 我不知道
No, I didn't. I didn't.
是卡拉狄加发明了那种病毒吗?
Was the virus created by Galactica?
自从你登船以后  你和他们联系过吗?
D'ANNA: Have you been in contact with them since you've been on onboard,
或者说 在那次新卡布里卡大撤退之前就开始计划了?
or did you plan this before the evacuation of New Caprica?
这是一个很大的误解
This is a most profound misunderstanding.
我和那个病毒或那个信标没一点关系
No. I had nothing to do with the virus or the beacon.
没错 我在基地之星上确实看到了它
Yes. Yes, I did discover it on the Baseship
我是应该把这个情况及时跟你们说的 但是我没有
and I should have told you about it sooner, and I didn't.
因为我想你们会把病毒和我…
Because I thought, you know, you'd try and link me, you know,
联系起来 事实也是如此
to the virus, which is what is going on right now.
我错了 那是个错误
I was wrong and it was a mistake,
我完全承认我有责任
and I fully admit my responsibility.
再也不会有这种事情了
It will never happen again,
并且我希望你们接受我最真诚的歉意
and I hope you accept my most, you know, my most humble apology.
我正在对那个道标的来历进行研究
On a brighter note, I have a working theory as to where this beacon may...
对不起 盖尤斯
I'm sorry, Gaius.
如果你告诉我们真相  事情会更简单些
Things would've been so much simpler had you only told the truth.
我们认为你知道更多的病毒信息 我们得找出来
We think you know more about this virus and we intend to find out.
放松 喝点东西吧
Relax, have a drink.
我办不到
I can't.
疼 疼
The pain, the pain...
都是在你脑里的 盖尤斯
It's all in your head, Gaius.
疼痛  快乐  那只是神经系统反馈给大脑的
Pain, pleasure, they're just neural impulses sent to the brain.
是你决定怎么去解读这些信息
You decide how to interpret them.
它们可以是愉快的或者不愉快的
They can be pleasant or unpleasant.
不  不 请别这样!
No! No, please!
求你们了!
Please! No!
我也想停下来了 盖尤斯
I want it to stop, Gaius.
我不想让你感受这种痛楚
I don't want you to feel this pain.
卡布里卡  你也不想  对吧?
And neither does Caprica. Do you?
是的
No.
我爱你
I love you.
你有什么感觉吗?
You feel anything yet?
是的 我感觉恶心  被你烦得恶心
Yeah. I feel sick. Sick of you bugging me.
你没有接触任何感染的尸体
You didn't touch any infected skin jobs.
不是我的错 是你们笨
It's not my fault you're clumsy.
你可以亲我感染了的屁股
You can kiss my infected ass.
很好 你可以亲它  但它没有被感染  我把血检结果带来了
Well, you can kiss it, but it's not infected. I got your blood work back.
人类对这种病毒是免疫的 你们都是健康的
Humans are immune to the virus. You're all healthy.
谢谢
Thank you.
好的 伙计们 干得好 让我们离开这里吧
All right, people, nice job. Let's get out of here.
让我们离开这里吧
PILOT: Come on, let's get out of here.
你不行 你要多待一段时间
No. You stay put for a while.
是
Yes!
不 不 不 不 请告诉我她没问题吧
No, no, no, no, no. Please. Tell me she's okay.
我还没做她的血检呢
I haven't done her blood work yet.
什么?
What?
我知道了 她可以等 因为她不是人
I see. She can wait because of who she isn't.
莎伦?
Sharon?
你会没事的 我保证
You're gonna be okay, I promise.
你是冲着我来的 该死的
You come for me, Gods damn it,
你这样做就是冲着我的 你知道的
you come for me the second you know.
把他带走 他快不行了
Take him. He's the furthest gone.
不 不 不
No! No! No.
你可以让赛昂人活下去?
ROSLIN: You can keep the Cylons alive?
我没把握治愈他们 不过没错…
I can't cure them, but yes.
多长时间?
How long?
还不确定
Indefinitely.
我识别出了病毒 我们把它叫做淋巴球性脑炎
I identified the virus. We know it as "Lymphocytic encephalitis. "
是啮齿目动物会得的病 多数是鼠科
The disease is carried by rodents, rats, mostly.
但几百年以前 人类对它有了免疫性
But a couple of hundred years ago, humans developed an immunity.
现在我也可以做出一个简单的疫苗
Now I can create a simple vaccine
可以把赛昂人体内病毒引起的病状明显改善
that will dramatically reverse the effect of the virus on the Cylons.
但是 他们的血液里有抗体
But they have an antibody in their blood
会把疫苗的RNA给破坏
which breaks down the RNA of the vaccine.
那样它们就需要高频率、短间隙的注射疫苗
So they will need regular, close-interval injections
否则他们就会死
of the vaccine or they will die.
我能问个难听的问题吗?
Can I ask the ugly question here?
能找出一个让它们继续活着的理由吗?
Is there any reason to keep them alive?
我们可以审问一些情报
We could interrogate them for intelligence.
我同意 我们有很多未解的疑问
I agree. We have a lot of unanswered questions.
那好 就这样        但它们不会说的
Yeah, okay, but they're not gonna talk.
我们给它们疫苗的时候它们就会说的
ROSLIN: Well, they might if we dangle the vaccine.
它们也没必要知道那只是短期有效 而不是痊愈药剂
They don't need to know it's a stopgap, not a cure.
它们在被感染的船上做了祷告
They prayed on the infected ship.
西洛的老婆说 那是个叫做 "什么什么云的祈祷"
Karl's wife said it was something called, "The Prayer to the Cloud of Unknowing,"
管他妈的是什么
whatever the hell that is.
总之 关键是她说 它们只会在面对
Anyway, the point is, she said they only use it
最终的死亡的时候
when they're facing an imminent death that is final,
没有重新下载的机会时
no possibility of downloading.
它们在准备面对死亡
They're ready to die.
他们可能是准备好要死了
They may be ready to die,
但是这并不意味着他们不会再跳起来
but it doesn't mean that one of them won't jump at a second chance.
它感染了所有的东西
It infected everything,
基地之星 赛昂武士 突袭机
the Baseship, Centurions, Raiders,
直到我们被别的赛昂人飞船彻底遗弃
and so we were finally abandoned by the other Cylon ships.
为什么?
Why?
为什么不把你们隔离起来直到找到治疗的方法?
Why not just put you under quarantine until they found a cure?
是怕病毒会扩散
Fear of spreading the disease.
他们告诉我们 在病原体的组成中
They told us that there was a bio-electric feedback component
有一个生物电反馈部分
to the pathogen.
它会破坏我们大脑对免疫系统的控制
It corrupts how our brains manage our immune systems.
如果我们死掉并被复活 病毒也会跟着
If one of us dies and is resurrected, the disease will follow,
感染复活船 还有舰队
infecting the Resurrection ship and the Fleet.
你们为什么会在这里首先出现?
Why were you in this area in the first place?
我们被派过来
We were sent.
我们被派到这儿来寻找狮子星云
We were sent here to look for the Lion nebula.
波塔尔说狮子星云会指出通往地球之路
Baltar said it would point the way to Earth.
你刚才说什么?
What did you just say?
波塔尔...波塔尔还活着?
Baltar... Baltar's alive?
波塔尔在我们的基地之星上
Baltar is on our Baseship.
他在帮我们寻找地球
He's helping us find Earth.
他在用我们的导航图 还有我们从科波上发现的地图
He's using our navigation charts along with our map of Kobol.
他在带它们找地球
He's leading them to Earth.
我们想要一个新的开始
We want a new beginning,
多像你们
much like you.
我告诉了你们信息
I gave you information.
她说会有解药
She said that there was a cure.
科特尔医生会给你药物的
Doc Cottle will be giving you the medicine.
把他带回医务室
Take him back to the infirmary.
是 长官
MARINE: Yes, sir.
这有什么好笑的?
What the hell is so funny?
我想我找到了一个方法 可以解决掉我们的麻烦
I think I just thought of a way to solve all of our problems,
可以把赛昂人的威胁一次性地全部消除
to get rid of the Cylon threat for once and for all.
我们可以把它们全部消灭 灭掉整个赛昂人种族
We can wipe them out. We can destroy the entire Cylon race.
我们可以跳跃到一个已知的赛昂人补给线地域
APOLLO: We jump to an area we know the Cylons use as a supply line,
星云坐标2539
NCD2539.
我们在那儿故意暴露 我们假装要向它们寻战
We stay there, exposed. We look as if we're spoiling for a fight.
它们会派出舰队
They'll send their fleet.
只要有舰队 那就肯定有复活船
And where there's a fleet, there's a Resurrection ship.
只要复活船在我们范围内
Now, once the Resurrection ship is within our reach,
我们处死这里受感染的囚犯 接着撤退
we execute our infected prisoners. We bug out.
被处死的囚犯就会在复活船下载
The executed prisoners download into the Resurrection ship
它们还带着病毒
and with them, the virus.
你肯定病毒能下载到它们新躯体里吗?
You're sure the virus will download to a new body?
是赛昂人自己肯定的
The Cylons are sure of it.
它们把自己的病号都留在那里等死 毫无挽救的希望
They left their wounded out here to die alone with no hope of being rescued,
还告诉我们想知道的东西
that tells me all I need to know.
只要病毒在复活船上
And once the virus is in the Resurrection ship,
它们就停不了了
there'll be no stopping it.
去救助的人就可以成为瘟疫的携带者
Rescuers become carriers of the plague.
赛昂人自己都不相信它们能找到治疗方法
The Cylons themselves don't believe that they'll develop a cure.
噢 我的天
My Gods.
这样就可以把赛昂人彻底消灭
This could be the end of the Cylons entirely.
永远的    屠杀?
Forever. Genocide?
那就是我们要做的?
So that's what we're about now?
它们不是人类 它们是被造出来的
They're not human. They were built, not born.
没有父亲 没有母亲 没有儿子 没有女儿
No fathers, no mothers, no sons, no daughters...
我有一个女儿 我还用我的胳膊抱过她
I had a daughter. I held her in my arms.
她是半人类
She was half human.
但它们是东西 是危险的东西
These are things, dangerous things.
这是我们一个消灭它们的机会
This is our one chance to be rid of them.
你可以说一些听起来合理的东西
You can rationalize it any way you want.
我们这么做 我们将它们灭族
We do this, we wipe out their race,
那么 我们就和他们没有什么区别了
then we're no different than they are.
上尉 我不认同你的看法
ROSLIN: Captain, I respectfully disagree.
是赛昂人首先发起攻击
The Cylons struck first in this war.
并且他们不满足于灭绝了数十亿的人类
And not being content with the annihilation of billions of human beings,
他们残酷地在星系间追逐我们
they've pursued us relentlessly through the galaxies,
想把我们全灭掉
determined to wipe us out.
他们试图在新卡布里卡上和我们共同生活
They tried to live with us on New Caprica.
你说什么?
What did you say?
他们试图在新卡布里卡上和我们共同生活
They tried to live with us on New Caprica.
你没在新卡布里卡待过 根据我的记忆 你没去过那里
You were not on New Caprica. To my recollection you didn't set foot there.
如此地不顾及你的几百名男女手下
So out of respect for the hundreds of men and women on your crew
在那个蛇窟里遭受的折磨
who suffered through that snake pit,
我希望没听到你刚才说的话
I'm gonna pretend I didn't hear that.
你能更好地为舰队服务  如果你能偶尔想想
You would serve your fleet well if you would remember occasionally
对于幸存下的人类来说
that the Cylons are a mortal threat
赛昂人是个致命的威胁
to the survival of the human race.
我在说的是:对和错
I'm talking about right and wrong.
我在说的是:我们丧失了自身的一部分灵魂
I'm talking about losing a piece of our souls.
没人想听 对吗?  那就从我来说吧
But no one wants to hear that, right? Let's keep it on me.
没错 我是和一个赛昂人结婚
Yeah, I'm married to a Cylon
多少次 她为我们大家吃尽了苦头
who walked through hell for all of us how many times?
同时 她还不是那个什么半个东西
And she's not half anything.
我们怎么知道没有其他与她同样的人呢?
Okay, how do we know there aren't others like her?
她做出了决定 她要做个人 他们也是人
She made a choice. She's a person, they're a race of people.
用生化武器把他们灭族 那就是一个反…
Wiping them out with a biological weapon is a crime against...
就是一个反人类罪
Is a crime against humanity.
但它们不是人类 它们是程序设定好的
But they're not human. They're programmed.
我们会考虑你所说的话 谢谢你们两个
We will take your input under advisement. Thank you both.
谢谢 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
解散
Dismissed.
我可以帮你
I can help you.
我可以让你度过这折磨
I can guide you through the torment and beyond,
但你要做点事
but you'll have to do the work.
我会做任何事 任何事!
I'll do anything. Anything!
那就告诉我们想知道的
Then tell us what we want to know.
病毒是怎么创造出来的?  有治愈方法吗?
How was the virus invented? Did they make a cure?
看着我 看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
当你和我做爱的时候 盖尤斯
When you make love to me, Gaius,
你不是总想着我的
you don't always think about me.
你的思维漂走了 我知道的
Your mind wanders, I know that.
你会想到方程式、难题 你要烫洗的衣服
You think of equations, puzzles, your laundry...
那是大脑的本能 断开和身体的连接
It's the nature of the mind to disconnect from the body and journey on its own.
将你的思维与身体分离 把你的思维留在那个房间
Separate your mind from your body. Keep your mind in that room.
用你的智力来对付她
Use your intellect against her.
理由 逻辑 分析
Reason. Logic. Analysis.
寻找她心灵的漏洞
Find the holes in her psyche.
我不能啊 很疼
I can't. The pain...
疼痛只存在你的身体里 让你的身体与我在一起吧
The pain is only in your body, so keep your body here with me.
别担心 我会好好照顾它的
Don't worry, I'll care take of it.
你看 盖尤斯  这就是不疼的感觉
D'ANNA: You see, Gaius, this is what the absence of pain feels like.
很容易忘掉疼痛
It's easy to forget.
我和病毒没有关系 那只是个巧合
I had nothing to do with the virus. It was a coincidence.
没有巧合这个说法
There's no such thing as coincidence.
世界是按照上帝的旨意运作的
God wills the universe according to His design.
现在专注于她 把她当成赛昂人 而不是女人
Now focus on her as a Cylon, not a woman.
并以科学家的眼光 测试她的信念
Be a scientist. Examine her faith.
你的分析结果呢 博士?
What's your analysis, Doctor?
我是个科学家
I'm a scientist.
并且作为一个科学家
And as a scientist,
如果上帝存在
I believe that if God exists,
那我们对他的了解是不完全的    为什么呢?
our knowledge of him is imperfect. Why?
因为我们现有的故事和神话
Because the stories and myths we have
是由人编撰出来的 人是时间的过客
are the products of men, the passage of time.
这种宗教是基于这么一个前提 无法被证明
The religion you practice is based on a theory, impossible to prove,
你现在完全地信任神话
yet you bestow it with absolutes like
就像"没有巧合这个说法"
"there is no such thing as coincidence. "
这叫信念
It's called faith.
对上帝意志的完全信仰就意味着万物的存在都有理由
Absolute belief in God's will means there's a reason for everything.
万物!
Everything!
还有现在...
And yet,
你不禁自问 上帝如何行使死亡与毁灭
you can't help ask yourself how God can allow death and destruction,
然后鄙视自己的疑问
and then despise yourself for asking.
但现实是 如果我们能知道上帝的旨意
But the truth is, if we knew God's will,
那我们就都是神了 不是吗?
we'd all be Gods, wouldn't we?
我可以从你的眼里看出 戴安娜
I can see it in your eyes, D'Anna.
你失落 你矛盾 让我来帮你吧
You're frustrated. You're conflicted. Let me help you.
让我来帮助你改变吧
Let me help you change,
找到一个...能让你的信仰与现实统一的办法
find a way to reconcile your faith with fact,
找到一条通往理性世界的道路
find a way towards a rational universe!
我不知道你在玩什么游戏
I don't know what your game is,
但那是没用的
but it's not going to work.
你故意把我们的一艘船引到那个信标那儿 是不是?
You intentionally led one of our ships to that beacon, didn't you?
把你的身体交给我 只把你的思维留下
Give your body to me. Only your mind is there.
感受我 感受这些而不管她给你的疼痛
Feel me. Feel this where she wants you to feel pain.
看着我 看着我 盖尤斯
Look at me. Look at me, Gaius.
你想让我相信你是值得被拯救的吗?
Do want me to believe you're worth saving?
你想吗? 你想吗? 说出来
Do you? Do you? Say it.
我想让你信任我
I want you to believe in me!
别停下! 别停下!
Don't stop. Don't stop!
请 请你别停下
Please! Please don't stop!
你一定会信任我的 你是我的全部
You have to believe in me, you're all I have left!
现在告诉我 你信任我
Now tell me you believe in me.
告诉我 你相信我的力量
Tell me you believe in my strength.
我信任你! 我信任你!
I believe in you! I believe in you.
我爱你
BALTAR: I love you.
我全心全意的爱你
I love you with all my heart.
我全心全意地爱你
怎么样?
How?
科特尔医生说与怀过半人类的小孩有关
Cottle said it had something to do with carrying a half-human child,
婴儿的血细胞进入到了母体的循环系统
how the fetal blood cells enter the maternal circulatory system,
让我也拥有了抗体 不管怎么样 我是免疫的
causing the mother to create antibodies, whatever. I'm immune!
噢 上帝啊
Oh, you.
我们的孩子救了我的命
Our baby saved my life.
她永远地走了 还救了我的命  赫拉与我们同在
She's gone forever and she saved my life. Hera kept us together.
分享这些
To share this.
这些?
"This"?
你说我们?  一起?  你说我们?
What, you mean us, together? You mean us?
他们  他们  我是说他们
Them, them. I mean them.
谁是"他们?"
Who's "them"?
他们准备处死被感染的囚犯
They're gonna execute the infected prisoners,
但要到跳跃进入赛昂人的地界
but not until we jump into a Cylon region,
在复活船范围内
with a Resurrection ship present.
那样就能感染到各处
The infection's gonna spread everywhere.
我想说一点
There's a point I'd like to make.
法律禁止我们使用生化武器
The law forbids me to use biological weapons
在没有总统命令的情况下
without a direct presidential order.
那意味着你要遇到麻烦了
Which means you're passing the buck.
在这件事上 是的
On this one, yes.
西洛在这件事上是对的
Helo's right on one thing.
我们在毁灭整个种族 哪怕它们是机器种族
We start destroying entire races, even mechanical races,
我们会遭受心灵的谴责
we're liable to tear off a piece of a man's soul.
赛昂人在寻找地球
The Cylons are coming to Earth.
如果它们找到我们 他们就会袭击我们
If they find us, they are coming for us.
它们都是木头脑袋 它们一直都是这样的 比尔
Those are the stakes. They always have been, Bill.
我们说的是你整个种族的屠杀
We're talking about the genocide of your entire race.
是的 你以为我不知道吗
Yeah. You think I don't know that?
我做了穿上这身制服的决定
I made a choice to wear a uniform.
来当个人
To be a person.
你在穿上这身制服前 就已经是人了
You were a person before you put on that uniform, okay?
你在与我相爱前就已经是个人了
You were a person before I fell in love with you.
你不需要证明这个
You don't have to prove that.
我每天都要证明
I have to prove it every day.
让我告诉你 西洛
Let me tell you something, Helo.
我们的人可能会死掉 整个族群可能会被灭掉
My people may die, my entire race may be wiped out,
但这个赛昂人会一直遵守她的诺言
but this Cylon will keep her word,
哪怕那意味着她是世界上唯一的赛昂人
even if it means she's the last Cylon left in the universe.
这是否有哪个人类能做到呢?
Can a human being do that?
我们的后代不会宽容我们的种族灭绝计划
Posterity really doesn't look too kindly on genocide.
你只是在假设我们的后代会把这定义为种族灭绝
You're making an assumption that posterity will define this as genocide.
如果他们这样想 至少他们还可以活着来憎恨我们
If they do, at least there'll be someone alive to hate us for it.
赛昂人的产生是我们的错误 我们创造了他们
The Cylons are our mistake, we created them.
好吧 阿达玛上将
All right, Admiral Adama,
作为总统  我决定赛昂人要被消灭
as President, I have determined the Cylons be made extinct.
生化武器的使用已被授权
The use of biological weapons is authorized.
齐心协力
So say we all.
跳跃完毕 雷达上显示没有赛昂人 长官
Jump complete. Dradis is clear, no Cylons, sir.
它们一会儿就会来的 让我们的"小鸟"上天吧
They'll be here soon enough. Get our birds in the air.
命令蝮蛇战机与导航侦察猛禽机升空
Commence Viper and nav Raptor launch.
又是那里 关了它 走吧
CREWMAN: Once more there! Let's get it closed. Let's go!
我们干吧  赛道
Let's do this, Racetrack.
行动 行动
CREWMAN 1: Let's go, let's go, let's go!
准备发射道
CREWMAN 2: Prepare the tubes!
旋压向上
CREWMAN 3: Spinning up.
准备好了
CREWMAN 4: All up!
行动 行动 把那些挪走
Let's go! Let's go! Move them back!
快行动 快行动!跟上!
Let's go! Let's go! Come on!
CAP编队升空  导航机已在雷达上看到
Cap is away. Nav Bird has them on Dradis.
雷达发现目标 一队赛昂人突袭机
Dradis contact. Pair of Cylon Raiders.
和它们保持距离
Keeping their distance for now.
不要花太长时间 它们只是侦查机
Didn't take them that long. It's just scouts.
它们会跳跃走  向舰队报告
They'll jump away and report back to their fleet.
来看我们有没有什么圈套的
See if they take our bait.
发现它们了 它们中有一艘复活船
Got it. There's a Resurrection ship with them.
是对我们的赛昂人囚犯执行死刑的时候了 下命令
Then it's time to execute our Cylon prisoners. Call it in.
处死囚犯
Terminate the prisoners.
射击头部 好吗?
Head shots, okay?
是 长官
Yes, sir.
让我们搞定
Let's do it.
好了 让我们看看能否干掉些烤面包机 伙计们
Let's see if we can't frak up some toasters on this joyride, people.
大家一起加油  我在上面感觉要死哦
HOTDOG: Bogies holding hands, I'm notching like hell up here!
热狗 我是星芭
Hot Dog, Starbuck.
闭上你的臭嘴 继续掩护我们
Quit your bitching and continue to cover us, frak!
好 让开
All right, out of the way.
妈的! 它们全死了  它们都死了
Frak! They're already dead. They're already dead.
长官 你应该听下这个
Sir, you should hear this.
它们在复活船出现前都死了
APOLLO: They were dead before the Resurrection ship was in range.
它们没有下载病毒 我们失去机会了
They didn't download the disease. We have missed our window.
卡拉狄加  星芭  基地之星刚跳跃过来
Galactica, Starbuck. The Baseship just jumped in.
招回我们的"小鸟"  撤离
Call our birds in. Spool up.
让我们离开这鬼地方
Let's get the hell out of here.
执行命令 西奥       是 长官
Commence it, Theo! Yes, sir!
长官 我们没机会听好消息了
Sir, we've lost time waiting to hear from quarantine.
我们想好好打一仗的在我们撤退的时候
We're going to take significant fire while we spool up.
等等
Wait a minute.
继续跳跃
Continue jump.
让我们回舰队去
Take us back to our fleet.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
他们会来找我麻烦的 你或是我
They're coming for me. You or me.
看起来他们会经常找我们之一的麻烦
It seems like they're always coming for one of us.
我不是个叛徒 我爱我的人民 我爱这艘船
I'm not a traitor. I love my people, I love this ship.
除了你 我在早上最想能看到的就是作战指挥中心里的灯光
Besides you, the first I want to see on any morning are the lights in that CIC.
我做了我认为是对的事
But I did what I thought was right.
如果那是个错误 也行 我可以承受
If it was a mistake, fine, I can live with that.
但是没有你 我活不下去
It's you I can't live without.
我会永远爱你 西洛
I'll always love you, Helo.
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
囚犯是因为窒息而死的
The prisoners died of asphyxiation.
空气净化系统被关闭 以伪装空气都跑光了
The air purification system was reversed. Sucked the oxygen out.
这时候 门上的保险拴
When this happens, the dead bolts
就会自动激活
are automatically activated on the door.
是有人动的手脚
Someone did this manually.
有人?
Someone?
在我看来 只有一两个嫌疑人
Seems to me there's only one or two likely suspects.
谁负责调查呢?
Who will head the investigation?
没人 我把这件事封锁了
No one. I'm closing the book on this.
多省心的决定啊
How convenient.
科特尔医生关于病毒的报告
Cottle's report on the virus.
他认为那个被我们丢在赛昂飞船上的道标
He thinks that it was simply an accidental contamination
被病毒污染只是个意外
of the beacon we abandoned on the sickbay ship.
可能是有人打了喷嚏造成的?
Somebody sneezed, maybe?
是啊 因为有人忘了擦干自己的鼻子
Yeah, an entire race almost wiped out
差点就能灭掉一整个种族
because someone forgot to wipe their nose.
根据科特尔所说 这个病毒非常符合
According to Cottle, the virus was an exact match
一个3000多年前被报告的病毒
to one reported over 3,000 years ago,
大概在那个时候 我们的第13部落离开了科波
right around the time that the Thirteenth Colony left Kobol.
那个信标是去地球的一个路标
That beacon was a signpost to Earth.
我们找对路了 劳拉
I think we're on the right trail, Laura.
是的 我们找对路了 比尔
Yes, we are on the right trail, Bill.
赛昂人也找对了
So are the Cylons.